Indiana University Daniel Read Residence Center Community Council minutes and other material, 1975-2002 C319
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Daniel Read Residence Center Community Council minutes and other material
1975-2002
1975-1990
Indiana University Archives
Daniel Read Residence Center (Indiana University, Bloomington). Community Council
C319
1 cubic foot 1 box
Completed in 1955, the Center was originally known as the Smithwood Center and intended as a new dormitory for female students. In 1960, the Center was renamed Daniel Read Residence Center to honor the late professor of ancient languages who taught Indiana University's first female students. The Council is made up of representative groups from within the Center, including center staff. It oversees any aspect of center life affecting students and staff and serves as an open forum for staff and students to proactively address center issues, to create center programming, to efficiently use community resources, and to help sponsor events. The collection spans the years 1975-2002 and consists primarily of minutes from Council meetings but also includes handbooks and manuals related to the Council and residence hall living. The folders, and the materials in them, are in their original order.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Administrative History
Construction on Daniel Read Residence Center began in June 1953. Completed in 1955, the Center was originally known as the Smithwood Center and intended as a new dormitory for female students. In 1960, the Center was renamed Daniel Read Residence Center to honor the late professor of ancient languages who taught Indiana University's first female students. By 1996 the building was home to upperclassmen in the Music department and was perceived as a quieter, more study focused place to live.
In place throughout the IU system, community councils oversee any aspect of center life affecting students and staff. The Daniel Read Residence Center Council is made up of representative groups from within the center, including center staff. It serves as an open forum for staff and students to proactively address center issues, to create programming, to use community resources efficiently, and to help sponsor events.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into two series: Minutes and Administrative files.
Scope and Content Note
The Daniel Read Residence Center Community Council collection is organized into two series: Minutes and Administrative files. The collection spans the years 1975-2002 with the bulk of the material coming from the years 1975-1990. The folders, and the materials in them, are in their original order.
The Minutes series spans 1975-1987. There are records of minutes from each council meeting that was held during the given year. Each folder also includes a list of the council members for the given year.
The Administrative files series, 1983-2002, includes manuals related to Read Center and the residence halls, resident assistant manuals, as well as other general files.
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory: http://instituionalmemory.iu.edu/aim/
Separated Material
Negatives from Read Center Picnic transferred to Archives Photographs Collection. Consult the Archives Photographs Curator for access.
Acquisition Information
Accession numbers 2005/076, 2005/097, 2006/034.
Provenance
Accession 2005/076 transferred from Tehanee Ratwatte, Daniel Read Residence Manager, August 3, 2005; Accession 2005/097 (photographic negatives) transferred from Tehanee Ratwatte, September 6, 2005. Accession 2006/034 (Little 500 materials) transferred from Tehanee Ratwatte, May 4, 2006.
Student housing --Indiana --Bloomington --Sources.; Student participation in administration --Indiana --Bloomington --Sources.; College student government --Indiana --Bloomington --Sources.; Daniel Read Residence Center (Indiana University, Bloomington). Community Council -- Archives; Daniel Read Residence Center (Indiana University, Bloomington). Community Council -- Records and correspondence
- Minutes, 1975-1987 (Box 1)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 1)
- Administrative files, 1983-2002
  - Read Center Handbook (Box 1)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - 1994 (Box 1)
  - Read Center Notebook, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Welcome Week Orientation, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Resident Assistant (RA) Manual, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Personnel Policies (Box 1)
    - 1995 (Box 1)
  - Department of Residence Life Diversity Education Manual, undated; (3 files) (Box 1)
  - Original Read Staff Manual, undated (Box 1)
  - Little 500 Duty, 1995-1999 (Box 1)